Finding Aid for the Brian Urquhart Collection of Material about Ralph Bunche, ca. 1932-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bahrain., 1970.; [Box 25, 2 folders]
  - Secretary General on Bahrain., March 28, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Press reaction. (Box 25, Folder 2)
- General., 1967-1971.; [Box 25, 6 folders]
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-G. Harrar (); R.J. Bunche-Secretary General (); confidential J.G. Harrar-J.Marshall (); R.J. Bunche-G. Harrar ()., September 21, 1966 August 29, January 30 and 6, 1967 June 24, 1966 March 30, 1967. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Press release: R.J. Bunche on future plans., February 28, 1967. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - RFK assassination., June 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Desk calendar., March 14-22 and April 8-10, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., May 11-18, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche statement re M.L. King's death., April 5, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche note., April-May 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Letters: A.J. Muste-E. Roosevelt, R.J. Bunche-E. Roosevelt ()., April 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Committee of 7's 14th meeting., May 7, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., July-August 1968. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-Nixon (); Secretary General-B.A. Clark (); R.J. Bunche-Ambassador E.O. Ogbu ()., December 2, 1968 February 6, 1968 January 15, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., June 17-24, 1967, January 25-February 1 and October 18-25, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Secretary General's public papers U Thant., 1968-1971. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Secret meeting with General Gowon in Lagos., January 18, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Confidential letter: Secretary General- General Y. Gowon., February 9, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., February 6 and April 25, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Notes on OPI Press Briefings., February 13 and July 11, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - OPI Daily Press Briefing., February 14, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General statement on death of D. Eisenhower., March 28, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Letters: V.J. Betts-R.J. Bunche ()., April 11 and August 26, 1969.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General to U.S. President re Apollo 11., July 24, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Itinerary for R.J. Bunche family., July/August 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., August, September 9-10 and October-November 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Notes on UNCA w/Rev. Paisley., September 9, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., October 18-25, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Note for Secretary General., September 19, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche diary on visit to 19th Pugwash conference., October 22-25, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's medical summary. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-Nixon ()., November 12 and 29, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Transcript of ABC's Issues and Answers., December 28, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Letter: V.J. Betts-R.J. Bunche ()., March 30, 1970.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - My Aunt Ethel by R.J. Bunche., April 26, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., October 1 and December 14, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Acceptance remarks by R.J. Bunche at Family of Man Awards dinner., October 26, 1970. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-A.C. Liveran ()., June 23, 1971. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Memo: strictly confidential M.H. Gherab-Secretary General re R.J. Bunche's resignation., June 9, 1971.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - UN conference news bulletin., October 1971. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Note to correspondents., October 1, 1971.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Press briefing by UK delegation., October 1, 1971. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Secretary General statement on R.J. Bunche's death., December 9, 1971.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Provisional record of 2008th General Assembly meeting., December 9, 1971. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - B.E. Urquhart's tribute to R.J. Bunche., 1971.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Ralph J. Bunche; Obituaries; Remembrances and Tributes., [Box 25, 1 folder]
  - Pamphlet: R.J. Bunche-The Man & His Times, R.J. Bunche memorial., May 5-6, 1986 November 1980. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - The Crisis: R.J. Bunche-Educator & Peacemaker., January 1972. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche tribute from J. Robinson ()., February 1, 1972. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Unforgettable R.J. Bunche by L.B. Pearson. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - UN note: R.J. Bunche's death anniversary., December 11, 1972. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Article: R.J. Bunche and Peace-keeping by B.E. Urquhart., 1973. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets: Peace Form One (); R.J. Bunche stamp ()., September 15, 1980 January 12, 1982. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - B.E. Urquhart & Ambassador Kirkpatrick re R.J. Bunche Stamp., January 12, 1982. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - W.T. Mashler., August 7, 1984. (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Atomic Energy Conferences., [Box 26, 1 folder]
  - UN Review: Atomic Energy conference., September 1956. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche diary re 19th Pugwash conference., October 22-25, 1969. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Confidential report: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General conversation., November 11, 1954. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - First Committee report re peaceful atomic energy uses., November 26, 1954. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Secretary General statement presented by R.J. Bunche at conference of International Atomic Energy Agency (); R.J. Bunche's statement at 3rd session ()., October 1, 1957 September 23, 1959. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Letters and statements from 5th General conference., September 26, 1961. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Thematic Index (Race Relations)., [Box 26, 1 folder]
  - Chronological Thematic Index: Race-Related Themes., 1935-1969. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Includes black leadership/black organizations; racism stereotypes; and democracy.
- Race - Related and Chronology, (Robeson, Dubois, Yergan, James, Washington)., 1935-1950.; [Box 26, 3 folders]
  - R.J. Bunche's My Most Unforgettable Character. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Biographical notes on R.J. Bunche, Under-Secretary General, UN. New York., 1970. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - IGS article R.J. Bunche & Howard School of Thought by C.P. Henry., May 1992. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Chronology., 1935-1941. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Letters: Jellife; H.J. Laski; A.W. Holcombe-R.J. Bunche; Coles-R.J. Bunche; R.J. Bunche-L. Hanke., 1941. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Memo: W.C. Haygood-E.R. Embree ()., May 21, 1941. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche note., March 2, 1948. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Focus article: Truman & Desegregation of Military by E. Dorn., May 1948. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Letters: A. Ernst-R.J. Bunche (); Senator McGrath-G.G. Hudson; R.J. Bunche-J.E. Marsh; J.A. Price-R.J. Bunche; W. Winchell-R.J. Bunche., April 20, 1949 1949. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche note., June 17, 1949. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's acceptance of 34th Spingarn Medal., July 17, 1949. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's Prejudice in World Prospective., May 24, 1954. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-L.F.Coles (); R.J. Bunche-M. Yergan ()., March 18, 1941 December 13, 1938. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlet: 2nd National Negro Congress., October 15-17, 1937. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - FBI memo re Council of African Affairs., May 19, 1945. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Leaflet: The Commonwealth., March 12, 1945. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Letters: P. Robeson-L. Pasvolsky (); DuBois-R.J. Bunche (); Frazier-R.J. Bunche (); W.E.B. Dubois ()., December 29, 1944 May 11, 1927, November 1935 January 29, 1951 February 27, 1957. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Press release: McCarthy Committee., July 10, 1953. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Race - Related and Chronological Binder., 1950-1960.; [Box 27, 2 folders]
  - R.J. Bunche notes: Paris trip, (); A & T Commencement ()., March 19-April 2, 1950 May 28, 1951. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-W.T. Thom ()., January 6, 1952. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlet: International significance of human relations by R.J. Bunche., February 12, 1951. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's Prejudice in World Perspective., April 24, 1954. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche address at NAACP conference, July 4, 1954., Typescript (carbon) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-J.T. Caldwell (); R.J. Bunche-J.W. McKenney (); R.J. Bunche-R.N. Lloyd (); R.J. Bunche-W.E. Johnson ()., July 1954 May, June 1955 April 1955 November 1955. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche speech at NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund dinner., May 17, 1956.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., February 2-9, 1957. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Questions & Answers: Jet Magazine., April 30, 1959. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche press clippings., 1959. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Term Negro by D. Livingfree. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche talk at 53rd NAACP Convention., July 6, 1962. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - American Baptist Convention 56th Meeting., May 18, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Meier-Broderick's Negro Protest Thought in 20th Century., June 16, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Race - Related and Chronology., 1960-1970.; [Box 27, 5 folders]
  - Race/Civil Rights listings., 1956-1968; & 1954-1959. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Speeches., 1954-1959. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's Prejudice in World Perspective., April 24, 1954. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Parade Magazine: Don't let them see you cry by A. Edwards, C.K. Polite., February 16, 1992. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - New York Times: The Deep South, 30 Years Later by P. Delaney., February 23, 1992. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Race/Civil Rights chronology., 1960-61. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Common Sense: How Red is NAACP & Its Leaders?., November 1, 1960. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Press clippings., 1960-61. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Speeches., 1960. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - R. Wilkins statement on Lumumba murder of demonstration at UN., February 15, 1960 1961. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., June 24-July 1, 1961; June 3-10, 1961. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-J. Robinson ()., November 1961. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's Emerging Africa and the UN for Manchester College., March 23, 1961.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Race/Civil Rights., 1961-1964. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Intellectual Development & Diplomatic Career of R.J. Bunche by Souad Halila nee El Agrebi., May 1988. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Press clippings., 1961. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's talk 53rd NAACP Convention., July 6, 1962. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Malcolm X and Adam Powell by J.Robinson., November 16, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-A.L. Reed ()., November 21, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Race/civil rights listings., 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Keesing's., November 30-December 7, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - New York Post., March 12, 1984. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Press clippings., 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Virginia council on human Relations., February 23, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Long Island Press., June 9, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's remarks at 51st Anniversary of July 4th celebration, Rebild National Park, Denmark., July 4, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's UN Commencement Address., June 10, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The UN in 1963., October 23, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Race/civil rights listings., 1964. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's., August 1-8, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - About Men by N. Mills - New York Times Magazine., October 28, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche speech Claremont Men's College., May 7, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's University Maine Commencement Address., June 5, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 4: Changing Times: The Watson Committee. (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Race Relations., 1965-1968.; [Box 28, 3 folders]
  - Press clippings folder., 1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Keesing's., October 16-23, 1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., March 24 and June 1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Alabama Petitn/March on Montgomery program & R.J. Bunche speech., March 25, 1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - World War II/Negroes., 1940. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Black leaders/organizations., 1939-1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - One Man's Outlook Commencement Address Hampton Institute., May 31, 1969. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche on the Rioting in Los Angeles., August 17, 1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Race/civil rights listings., 1966. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche Commencement Address University Wisconsin., June 5, 1966. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Race Relations situation., 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-Editor of New York Times., April 28, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., October 14-21 and January 28-February 4, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's Upheavals in the Ghettos., Typescript (carbon) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement Adam Clayton Powell., March 2, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Letter R.J. Bunche-T.H. McKee ()., March 4, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche note on Powell., March 8, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Letter: Secretary General-E. Cabell ()., March 24, 1967.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Press clippings folders., 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., April 20-27, 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Press clippings., 1967-1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-B. Kruger ()., March 14, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche note on representatives of Spring Mobilization., April 17, 1967. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes & personal statement on MLK., April 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Personal statement on the assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr., 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., May 11-18, 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - UCLA Noon Lecture Series Two Critical Dilemnas: Vietnam & the Ghetto., February 21, 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - The Black Revolution., August 20, 1968. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche diary notes., 1965-1966. (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Race Relations., 1969-1970.; [Box 28, 1 folder]
  - Transcript P. Frederick's Today Show., February 20, 1969. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche's remarks Bunche Hall Dedication., May 23, 1969. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche talk Race & Alienation., July 10, 1969. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Official daily press briefing., July 11, 1969. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Press briefing., July 1, 1970. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche: Seasons of Influence by J.D. Weaver. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Playboy interview: Andrew Young., 1969-1970. (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Speeches & Writings 1., 1927-1949.; [Box 29, 6 folders]
  - R.J. Bunche's That Man May Dwell in Peace., 1926. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's The 4th Dimension of Personality., June 1927.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlet: R.J. Bunche's The Negro in Chicago Politics., May 5, 1928. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's Light on the Dark Continent., 1927. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Random Impressions of an African Travelling., March 1938. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Modern Policies of Imperialistic Administration of Subject Peoples., April 5, 1935. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Galley: R.J. Bunche's A Critical Analysis of Tactics & Programs of Minority Groups., 1935. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche's Education in Black & White., July 5, 1936. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's A World View of Race., 1936. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - A Politico-Economic Analysis of Problems of Race in U.S.., May 24, 1936. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's Triumph? Or Fiasco?., 1936. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's Fascism and Minority Groups., July 2, 1936. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's Progress of Organizations devoted to improvement of status of American Negro., July 1939.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Analysis of Dynamics & Mechanisms of Negro Disfranchisement., 1939.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's Africa & Current World Conflict., 1940. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Notes 3rd National Negro Congress., April 26-28, 1940. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Memo: interview w/Mrs. FDR., May 15, 1940. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Excerpts from talk on position of Negro in Current International Crisis. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Memo: Negro Worker's struggle for economic justice., September 11, 1940. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Leaflet: Better Understanding Week., February 17-23, 1941. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - The Dilemma of the Negro., February 20, 1941. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Semitism in Negro Press., December 11, 1941. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Article: The Negro in Political Life of the U.S. Journal of Negro Education., July 3, 1941. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Dependent Territories Round Tables at Hot Springs., February 3, 1945. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Department of State Bulletin w/R.J. Bunche's Trusteeship & Non-self governing territories in UN Charter., December 30, 1945. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Human Relations in Modern World., April 1945-May 1946. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-I. Stolper ()., August 9, 1946. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's International Trusteeship & Accountability: the Problem of Colonies. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's Trusteeship & Colonies in New Republic., October 28, 1946. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche address The Horizon Widens., February 9, 1947. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - The UN & Under-Privileged Peoples., February 11, 1948.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's An International Bill of Rights. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - CBS interview with R.J. Bunche Prospects for Peace in Palestine., December 27, 1948. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - New York Times Palestine Solvent by S.P. Brewer. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Life Magazine U.S. Negro Makes Peace in Holy Land., March 14, 1949. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Dinner R.J. Bunche's honor., May 9, 1949.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - UN .. in Palestine., May 20, 1949. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - National Conference Christians/Jews., June 9, 1949. (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Ph.D. Dissertation (Incomplete)., [Box 30, 1 folder]
  - A Consideration of Colonial & Native Policies., n.d.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Summary of main ideas of Harvard dissertation.
- Speeches & Writings 2, (Including Race-Related Speeches)., 1950-1954.; [Box 30, 6 folders]
  - Index of race-related speeches., 1950-1959. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Schedule of press clipping., 1950-1959. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Some Reflections on Peace in Our Time., December 11, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Other People's Freedom (); Human Relations & Foundation for Peace (); Greater New York Fund (); Foundations for Peace ()., February 15, 1950 April 23, 1950 April 24, 1950 April 26, 1950.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - UN in Action., May 8, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - What America Means to Me., June 23, 1949. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - American Red Cross address., June 28, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Virginia State University commencement address., May 29, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Human Relations & World Peace., June 4, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Education & Peace Effort., June 11, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - American Red Cross address., June 28, 1950.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - UN Institute - New York University., 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Great Powers & the Near East., August 7, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Silver Jubilee Convention address., September 10, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - How UN Works for Peace., October 21, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - I Foresee an Era of Peace R.J. Bunche as told to A. George, In UN World (original copy)., November 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Some Reflections on Peace in our Time - Nobel Peace Prize Lecture., December 11, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - NAACP dinner., January 24, 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlet: International significance of Human Relations., February 12, 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Galley: FDR Four Freedoms Award Dinner., April 11, 1951.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Galley: Educating for International Peace & Understanding., April 12, 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Prospects for Peace., April 2 and 8, 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - University Michigan Commencement Address., June 15, 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlet: Atlanta University's Phylon Equality Without Qualifications & 42nd NAACP conference., July 1, 1951.; (2 copies) (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's introduction to R.N. Frye., 1951. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Galley: American Democracy's Challenge., February 29, 1952. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlet: Peace & the UN., March 13, 1952.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Galley: R.J. Bunche message to Veterans Committee., June 7, 1952. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - State Bar Association of Connecticut address., October 21, 1952. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - UN & World Crisis., November 13, 1952.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Toward Peace & Freedom March 15, 1953. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Pakistan Horizon: UN & World Tensions., June 1953. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Galley: One, Free World Dinner., June 4, 1953. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Vassar College commencement address., June 8, 1953. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - NAACP speech excerpts., March 10, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - WA Seminar on International Affairs., May 6, 1954.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Road to Peace., June 30, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - NAACP address () & LD & Education fund ()., July 4, 1954 May 17, 1956. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Johns Hopkins University Contemporary Africa., August 13, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Presidential address. American Political Science Association., September 9, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Galley: Sprngfield College., September 26, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 15 Million Americans., October 1, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlet: Presidential address., December 4, 1954.; (2 copies) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - St. Francis Peace Award., December 28, 1954. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche Statements., 1954, 1956. (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Speeches & Writings 3, (Including Race)., 1955-1959.; [Box 31, 4 folders]
  - R.J. Bunche convocation., November 13, 1959.; (Cassette) (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Publications list., 1928-1944. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Excerpts from statements by R.J. Bunche., 1950-1958. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Peace - Horizon of Hope/UN Role., June 24, 1955. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Galleys: UN after its 1st decade (); Michigan Press Association banquet (); UN in its 2nd decade ()., January 15, 1956 January 27, 1956 April 10 and May 10, 1956. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Galley: UN in proper perspective., May 3, 1956. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - 2nd annual NAACP Legal Defense & Education Fund on anniversary of Supreme Court's decision outlawing segregation in public schools., May 17, 1956. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Galleys: UN in Near E.: UN Emergency Force & Suez (); Foreign Policy from UN Perspective (); UN Emergency Force: from Talk to Operation, ()., April 20, 1957 April 8, 1958 April 11, 1958. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - UN Peace Effort in Near East., December 1, 1957. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Race Relations - World-wide view., March 16, 1958. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Youth Wants to Know Assistant., 1958. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's introduction of Dr. Kwame Nkrumah at Harlem Citizens Committee of 100., July 27, 1958. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Periclean Club Annual Forum., February 13, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Periclean Club Annual Forum., February 13, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Galleys: Some Implications, National & International Problem Race Relations (); UN Association Vienna (); Greater Detroit Chapter ()., February 23, 1959 September 29, 1959 October 18, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Long Beach State College commencement address., June 12, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche introduction of Honorable Nnamdi Azikiwe at NAACP., July 19, 1959. (Box 31, Folder 4)